M. Esat OZEN

Full Stack Software Developer Greater Boston Area, MA (203) 278 6572

ozenesat@gmail.com

https://ozenesat.github.io

https://github.com/ozenesat
https://linkedin.com/in/ozenesat

Skills

JavaScript React.js

Node.js

Next.js

Express Python

Ruby on Rails

Mongoose

MongoDB

NoSQL

PostgreSQL

Postman

Git/GitHub

Phabricator

Arcanist

jQuery

AJAX

JSON

Handlebars

HTML5

CSS3

Bootstrap

Linux/Ubuntu

Agile/Scrum

Education

Middle East Technical University (METU) Bachelor of Science

Mathematics

Abstract Algebra

Combinatorics

Complex Calculus

Cryptography

Discrete Mathematics

Introduction to C Number Theory

Leadership

President of the Student Council @ METU

Work Status

Green Card Holder

Summary

With a quantitative academic background and startup experience, able to master new skills quickly. Enjoys breaking down and solving complex problems with analytical thinking in transferring innovative ideas into the codebase. Experienced in diverse work areas in three different countries as a highly adaptive world citizen.

Experience

Rapic.io - Remote

May 2020 - Present

Front-End Developer

- Designed, implemented and tested the application from scratch with Next.js.
- Integrated Google, YouTube, Facebook, Twitch APIs for live stream and chat.
- Implemented OAuth functionality into the React application with backend server.
- Working with 6 developers globally over Phabricator in scrum methodology.

General Assembly - Boston, MA

February 2020 – May 2020

Software Engineer Fellow

- Completed 12 weeks/500+ hours of intensive Full Stack Development instruction.
- Built client-side applications with responsive behavior using JavaScript, React.
- Developed 4 full-stack web applications in four days sprints independently and collaboratively while practicing Agile methodology. Utilized Git for version control.
- Built RESTful APIs to store data for web-apps using Rails and SQL (PostgreSQL) or Express with MongoDB. Also integrated several third-party APIs.

Featured Projects

- <u>Photo Collector:</u> React application with Google Authentication and Unsplash API. {React, Node, Express, MongoDB, JS, OAuth} <u>Front-End Repo</u> <u>Back-End Repo</u>
- <u>Survey Says:</u> Full-stack, team project for single page online survey application. {React, Node, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose} <u>Front-End Repo</u> <u>Back-End Repo</u>
- <u>The Lists:</u> Single page to-do list application with Handlebars and Bootstrap techs. {AJAX, jQuery, JS, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL} <u>Front-End Repo</u> <u>Back-End Repo</u>
- <u>QMic.online:</u> Start-up project which allows live broadcasts get online guests with `n to 1` communication principle. {React, Redux, Python, PostgreSQL, OAuth}

Ace It Education - Boston, MA

May 2019 – February 2020

Web Developer

- Built and maintained two websites for the company's DBAs with WordPress.
- Managed e-mail accounts with G-Suite and e-mail campaigns with MailChimp.
- Provided technical support for the weekly events and classes of the company.
- Created social media and website content. Advertised the events via Eventbrite.

The Fix - Farmington, CT

May 2018 – May 2019

Store Manager

- Managed the finances of the company's branches at four different locations.
- Efficiently managed a yearly budget of ~\$1 million and increased the profitability of the company by 10% with user and market research.
- Worked on improving sales strategies and customer satisfaction. Established the use of alternative products and services tailored to customer needs.